Come on, do it!
It's up!
She'll be begging for mercy when I'm done with you, Ushiwaka!
You're gonna have to come through me first if you wanna take down Ushiwaka.
You're gonna have to come through me first if you want.
光あれ行け 闇をかそろりして 己の道を経験に誇こう
光あれ椅子先の絶望へ 二寸先の栄光を信じて
光あれ椅子避ける理由はたった一つ 光あれもっと眩く俺はもうめぐ
光あれ君の今日の輝きが 迷える友の明日を照らすよ
光あれ椅子先より脳行き大人 目を捉えて
光あれ Munister
謳 unasきれた場所ね
この天命をあった
魔害を止めて
首度で最初に危 baskets
Did he just call number five a guest mobster?
Is he gonna put a hit out on poor Hinata?
This game's so dangerous!
I don't think you guys heard that right.
Send it over!
Sorry!
Kageyama, last for you!
Don't let him get that point!
Blocking isn't just the art of stopping the ball.
Goshki, help me stop the straight.
It's the art of smashing it down, too.
That has got to be really disheartening for our guys.
When you can't get around clean blocks like that,
it can really hurt your morale.
Feeling good!
Get the next one!
It's okay, Kageyama!
If at first you don't succeed,
try and try again!
Yeah, nice receive.
Too easy.
Man, it feels like I'm playing at 120% today!
How is he able to react so quickly?
It's not just his reaction time.
I mean, within that mere split second,
he analyzed three possible problems from us.
First, since Kageyama's up front,
we could have pursued a dump.
So he had to guess whether or not that was going to be attempted.
But if not, he had to guess at who was going to be our attacker.
Was it going to be Tanaka or Hinata in the front?
Or Asahi or Daichi in the back?
Then assuming the ball was going to Hinata,
which it did,
he had to guess where he was going to aim.
We have an advantage to see these things.
We have a bird's eye view of the court.
But down there, it's hard keeping tabs on everything in real time.
Sometimes your body doesn't react as quickly as your brain.
But with him, his body and mind are both in sync.
Not surprised we're taking a timeout after that.
I could have sworn that they were going to go for a back attack for sure.
I mean, their setter even glanced back behind him.
That was a very obvious bait.
Huh? Karasu no setter is pretty good, I'll give him that.
But that seemed a little too deliberate.
Glances, footwork, and that movement.
If Tendo picks up on any of your tells you, I don't fuck.
Oh, I thank you.
Sorry, bud. I'm not sharing the spotlight this game, my man.
Hmm. It's not a big deal.
Shit up, guys! We're taking this next point!
No biggie, Hinata! Get us the next one!
Will do!
Huh? Kageyama, your face! You mad, bro?
This is my normal face.
Liar!
The only thing that pisses me off more than when my own spikes get knocked down
is when it happens to be the ones that I set up perfectly.
How's number five able to consistently shut us out like that, coach?
Hey, Spex, you know what a read block is, don't you?
It's where the player reacts after he sees where the ball's being set.
Yeah. And read in this context doesn't simply mean to read the current situation,
but also to understand it as well. If you jump after watching the ball,
there's little danger in getting tricked by the set. Your reaction is a little delayed,
but if you can get a three-man block up, you'll pretty much lock out anything thrown at you.
We're still working on this ourselves.
Shiratori Zawa's number five is really gifted at making his reads, though.
He's coupling his reads with his intuition, so his guest blocking is where he shines.
He's anticipating the attack before the set, based almost entirely on his instinct.
He's psychic?
Naturally, there will be times when his instincts are way off,
and when that happens, it could really screw up his teammates' blocks or receives.
To put it simply, this playstyle's results vary based on the individual,
but I think number five's guesses are insanely accurate,
and it appears his body is able to keep up with his mind.
I think it's best if we assume his movements adhere to no pattern.
Don't overthink him or let him distract you.
Yes, sir!
Okay, so how do you think we can prevent him from reading all of our sets?
Maybe we should have Kageyama channel his inner Hinata and do some messy feints.
I'd actually love to see that.
One more pretty serve, pretty please!
Save it up front!
Sorry, I hit that short!
They don't realize their feints are useless against Tendo.
So, this is what being a well-oiled machine looks like.
I got lost in thought.
By the time I realized where the set was going, they already spiked it.
You said that last one right over my head.
That took some cojones, knowing what I'm capable of.
You must be a pretty sore loser, huh?
I knew you guys would be fun to play!
It's a change ball!
I screwed up!
It's coming back!
On it!
Hey, I got it!
I think it's best if we assume his movements adhere to no pattern.
Don't overthink him or let him distract you.
Also, with opponents like this one, it's important to use the width of the core to your advantage.
Aren't you a quick little stinker?
All right, that ties us!
Nice kill!
Oh, yeah!
Come on, Spoon!
That's incredible!
Oh, yeah!
There have been setters I admire for trying to get around my reads before, but that number 10's timing is insane.
I have to keep up because if I fall even just one tempo behind, it's almost as if the ball somehow teleports beyond my reach.
So I assume you want us to overlook your little screw-up from earlier, right?
Guess so.
Puns are the lowest form of comedy.
Show us what you got!
Nice receive!
This is our chance to attack!
One touchy!
Got it!
I can't tell if that was a feint or he changed his mind mid-play.
Now he feels like Shira Torizawa is unpredictable on all fronts.
I just can't figure it out. What's number five's playing style?
He wants to stop every spike all by himself.
You can look at it this way. Tendo's blocks have been used to score points against us.
They've been reversing all our spikes into points for their team.
In other words, there's more to blocking than simply stopping the ball.
If we can manage to block and maintain control, we'll be able to pull out ahead of this.
That can lead to some points for us as well.
So the point is, depending on how it's timed, blocking can be more valuable than spiking is in some instances.
Interesting.
Don't let them pull ahead.
If they get the opportunity, they're going to leave our guys in the dust.
It's like they hit that on purpose just to silence the haters.
Rishiwaka is really playing on another level today.
Blocks ultimately evolve in order to stop attacks.
And then those attacks evolve in order to break through those new blocks.
Huh?
Attacks get more diverse when you throw in other elements.
Like the back row, speed attacks, and combos.
This leads to adapting variations in blocks, positions, and even how one jumps.
Players who think that they are at the top of their game,
keep finding new ways to climb higher than they thought was possible.
Looks like you've been studying specs.
Just observations.
I'm sure that they will keep striving for new heights with their tenacity and fighting spirit.
Great plays can save the team, but even more so can the power of reason.
It's Mr. Vanilla!
Don't let him get under your skin.
Serve it up, Tai Chi!
That's gonna fall!
That's a chance ball! Chance ball!
Damn it!
Sorry, guys!
Is this going to be a lag attack?
Uh-oh!
Hello. I'm Mr. Vanilla.
Your timed lag attack.
It might have been able to trip up our feral child, but it won't work on me.
Continue to use it, though.
I thought Karasuno's first years were just annoying little punks,
but you really are a cut above the rest.
Why, thank you.
You're pissing me off!
Serve it up, Asahi!
Please keep a level head.
You're Karasuno's voice of reason.
We'll be fine.
We're definitely going to get our chance.
Feels like Yamaguchi is staring a hole right through my head.
One touch!
I got it!
This guy is bugging me.
That one's for you, Koski, you idiot!
Don't just stare at the ball!
Do something!
Uh, yes, sir.
Oh, Koski.
Here I thought the infamous demon, Koj, might actually be chilling out in his old age.
Go get him!
Suga, let's do this!
In the front ray on!
It's time for a synchronized attack!
Yeah!
Nice one, Kaviyama!
What was that?
Am I going blind and senile?
Did the center just make that?
No, the arrogance!
Guess being disrespectful is a family trait!
Oh, that's right.
Karasuno's head coach is Coach Yukai's grandson, isn't he?
That's right.
That imbecile Yukai always relied too much on gimmicks to make up for weaknesses.
That old geriatric bastard!
It's archaic to rely only on a single player to carry your team.
And you're totally reckless by sending the entire team to attack so no one's left to follow up!
Sadly, because the high school roster changes every year,
we're limited to what we can achieve.
Polishing what raw materials we have is our best bet.
Let's go!
It's how we'll find success.
Man, that old coach Washito hasn't changed a bit, has he?
His motto's simple as best.
He's always liked height and power.
In fact, he'd recruit anyone who met those standards, whether they'd ever played or not.
And regardless if there was even any room for them on the squad,
as long as they fit his definition of a powerhouse, they'd make the team.
He would work closely with his new recruits and put them through a grueling spartan-like training.
I see. So can the method he uses always produce an all-star player?
Of course not. Finding a player with Ushiwaka's height, power, and level of skill is just like hitting the lottery.
But when Washito finds someone like him, he's going to make him the axis of the team,
and make sure everyone knows their role.
That's just Shiratorizawa's style.
Man, Ushiwaka just will not let up!
This is definitely going to be an uphill battle, but we can still turn the tide.
Nice receive!
Keep it up, guys!
Nice kill, Boshki!
It's all you, Shirabu!
I have it! For you!
Whoa! Wait it down!
I'm so nervous, I'm having palpitations!
I think I am too.
With me around, you can beat anyone!
I can't bring myself to say confident things like Hinata.
I can, however, lend you my strength.
It's all you!
They're breaking up!
Yes!
This is it.
Sorry about that, Ushiwaka!
We're stopping him, guys!
Good. This will work.
All I need is just a high set.
This is what being strong really means.
Smash it, mash it into pieces!
Smash what?
They're hard until it ceases!
So it can't be fixed with adhesives!
Take it away!
They're blocks?
What the heck is wrong with that guy?
Well, well, man.
That jump in the glass this year has a punchable face.
Yo, Spex!
Right!
You know, that was a noble attempt, but even that serve didn't stop Ushiwaka.
Yeah, right?
I don't see...
Huh?
No nuts down there!
Sometimes they stop them, sometimes they go!
Now I know what you guys are thinking.
It would be really cool if we could break through their three-man blocks.
And that would boost morale, too.
However, don't get too far ahead of yourselves.
I know the tighter the score, the more eager you are to finish the game in one shot.
Not wise.
Every move, every play we make has to connect to the next.
The most important thing is to execute.
Since you look lost, Tina, that means slow it down.
I'm not stupid, you know!
I know I keep saying this, but even plays that don't lead to points are gonna benefit us in the long game.
This is our first five-set match.
It'd be a waste if you guys didn't enjoy the moment, just found it stressful, and didn't have any fun!
We're all out, boys!
Yeah!
Hey, guys.
Hmm?
About the three-man block we're using.
Could you please leave the timing up to me?
Shirabu!
Hmm?
Please think about when you pass to Ushiwaka.
Yeah, sure. Whatever.
I am serious!
Settle down, kids!
Give us a nice serve, Goshki!
Daiji!
Damn it.
That number one is good.
Hook us up with a nice serve, Daiji!
Goshki!
On it!
Nice one!
One touch!
You can't do it!
That's it, guys!
Perfect timing!
Connect it now!
Put it together!
What's the point of this?
They can't stop Ushiwaka!
Yeah, why is Karasuno's coach getting so happy so soon?
Doesn't he know this guy has a beast?
I got it!
That's a chance ball!
It's all you, Taiji!
All right, here it comes!
Looks like he knew to aim for our center.
Ushiwaka!
Cage him in.
Prioritize our blocking coverage and timing.
Make him sense our wall.
On my mark, ready, and...
That's it.
Your only path...
...is to our libero.
That's it.
All our plays are connected.
It's up there long enough to finally nail that receive.
They've been working so hard for it.
But it's going to be coming over here!
Or maybe not!
I knew that we'd be able to pull it off!
Now this is where the total defense begins!
Bye now!
Guys...
Later on, I want you to
You instead be пригlaimed
Don't wait to be able to face, rest
Later on, I want you to
Today, I don't want no we
teach with us
Covid-19 color
The cuidemandel is
This time
I kamp in
誇り高く生きたいのだ
後は君次第です
全部君次第
きっと甘い甘いと言われても
違うよ違う溶けなされたって
後は君次第
迷うんじゃない
君次第